A finding aid to the Hildreth Meière papers, 1901-2011, bulk 1911-1960 in the Archives of American Art AAA.meiemari
Archives of American Art
- Correspondence, bulk 1916-1961; 1901-2011; Series 2; 3 Linear feet Boxes 1-4, RD 19
  - Travel Correspondence (Box 3)
    Additional records related to Meiere’s travel are found throughout the collection. See Series 2, Correspondence, for correspondence written while abroad. See Series 4, Writings, for diaries and travelogues. Clippings and flyers related to talks and lectures given with the slides and films in this series are found in Series 6, Printed Materials. Films and photographs of subjects other than travel are found in Series 7, Photographs and Moving Images series.
    Travel Records are arranged in three subseries.
    Printed Material
    Slides
    Motion Picture Film
    - Hildreth Meière Letters from Paris, 1922 (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Hildreth Meière Correspondence with Spanish Relatives, 1925-1926 (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - Hildreth Meière Letters from Italy, 1927 (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Hildreth Meière Letters from Scandinavia and Paris, 1932 (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Hildreth Meière Letters from Turkey, Yugoslavia, and Paris, 1933 (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Letters from Robert, Paris, 1932-1933 (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - Hildreth Meière Letters from Germany, 1934 (Box 3, Folder 40)
      Includes a description of Meière's attendance at the Oberammergau passion play performance attended by Adolf Hitler in a letter of August 13, 1934, along with a transcription of the letter.
    - Hildreth Meière Correspondence with Spanish Contacts, 1935-1939 (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - Hildreth Meière Letters to Louise Harmon from Berlin, Poland, and Russia, 1936 (Box 3, Folder 42)
      Includes photographs
    - Letters to Hildreth Meière in Poland and Russia from Louise Harmon and Others, 1936 (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - Hildreth Meière Letters to Malvina Hoffman from France, 1938 (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - Letter from Jimmy Clarke to Hildreth Meière from Warsaw, Poland, 1939 January 29 (Box 3, Folder 45)
    - Hildreth Meière Letter to Louise Meière from Guatemala and Mexico, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 46)
    - Hildreth Meière Letters to Anne (Nancy) Basinger from South America, 1947 (Box 3, Folder 47)
    - Hildreth Meière Letters to Anne (Nancy) Basinger from the U.K. and Scandinavia, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 48)
    - Hildreth Meière Letters to Ellie from Uganda and Rome, 1953 March (Box 3, Folder 49)
    - Letters of Introduction for Hildreth Meière's Grand Tour, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Business Correspondence (Box 3)
    - Subject Index to Business Correspondence, 1999-2000 (Box 3, Folder 51)
    - A, 1933-1953 (Box 3, Folder 52)
      Includes letters from Berenice Abbott and Florence Allen.
    - Hartley Alexander, Scripps College, 1931-1940 (Box 3, Folder 53)
      Contains item list of letters
    - American Academy in Rome, Letters of Recommendation, 1920-1921 (Box 3, Folder 54)
    - American Institute of Architects, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 55)
    - Art Institute of Chicago, 1921-1922 (Box 3, Folder 56)
    - Art Students League, 1912-1916 (Box 3, Folder 57)
    - B, 1921-1944 (Box 3, Folder 58)
    - Bruno de Paoli and Co. (Huntington Seminary), 1943 (Box 3, Folder 59)
    - C, 1938-1940 (Box 3, Folder 60)
    - The Center Theatre, circa 1939 (Box 3, Folder 61)
    - Central Association of the Miraculous Medal (Mary Immaculate Seminary), 1938-1939 (Box 3, Folder 62)
      Also contains letters from R. Guastavino Company
    - Citizen's Committee for the Army and Navy, 1941-1944 (Box 3, Folder 63)
      See also series 4, Civilian War Service Records
    - G.H.A. Clowes (32nd General Hospital, Indianapolis), 1943 (Box 3, Folder 64)
    - Committee for the Mass Meeting for America, 1939 (Box 3, Folder 65)
      Multiple correspondents. Includes a printed program and clippings.
    - Cram and Ferguson (St. John's Church, Boston), 1936; 1925-1926 (Box 3, Folder 66)
    - Paul Phillippe Cret, 1935-1936 (Box 3, Folder 67)
  - Business Correspondence (Box 4)
    - D, 1928-1940 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - The Decorator's Club, 1940 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Baron Dervaux, 1937 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - E, 1938 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - John J. Early, 1936-1938 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Helen Farnham (Illinois Bell Telephone Co.), 1938-1940 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Lynn Faucett, 1937-1938 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Fordham University Chapel, 1942 (Box 4, Folder 8)
      Multiple correspondents.
    - Fred Harvey Restaurant and Cocktail Lounge, 1936-1937 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Emily Genauer, circa 1940 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Bertram Grosvenor Goodhue, 2000; 1921-1924 (Box 4, Folder 11)
      Contains item list of letters.
    - H, 1926-1969 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Inisfada, 1939 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Klimo, 1939 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Liturgical Arts Society, Inc., 1939 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - George Lovatt, 1936 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - M, 1936-1939 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Manhattanville College of the Sacred Heart, 1940 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - M.I.T School of Architecture, 1934-1935 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Hildreth Meière, 1932-1943 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Francis A. Nelson (St. James Church, Upper Montclair, NJ), 1943 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - New York Times, 1940 (Box 4, Folder 22)
      Contains typescript of poem Meière had published in the newspaper.
    - Obrero Lans Museum, 1937 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - P-R, 1926-1939 (Box 4, Folder 24)
      Contains letter from Alfred E. Poor.
    - Rambusch Decorating Company, 1933-1950 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Robert J. Reiley (Huntington Seminary), 1943; 1936 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - S-T, 1934-1957 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Joseph Sanford Shanley (St. Charles Borromeo Church, Newark, NJ), 1936-1937 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - St. James Church (Montclair, NJ), 1943 (Box 4, Folder 29)
      See also Francis A. Nelson
    - Smythe, Urqhart, and Marckwald, Inc. (S.S. United States), 1950-1951; 1939 (Box 4, Folder 30)
      See also series 6, Printed Material
    - Lizzie Stuart, circa 1939-1940 (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - U, 1943 (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - United States Navy, 1940-1942 (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - United States Treasury Department (Ed Rowan), 1935 (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - United States Treasury Department (Inslee Hopper), 1936 (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - F.R. Walker, 1936 (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - Wilfred Edwarts Anthony et al (St. Paul's Church, New Haven, CT), 1927 (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - Zantzinger and Borie, 1936 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Oversized Illustrated Letter on Scroll From Box 2, Folder 38 (Box RD 19)
- Writings, 1904-1960; Series 3; 1.3 Linear feet Boxes 4-5
  Arrangement is alphabetical by type of material. Additional material on Spanish Civil War is found in Series 4, Civilian War Service Records, and additional material related to Meiere’s travels is found in Series 2, Correspondence and Series 5, Travel Records.
  Writings include thirteen diaries spanning her childhood and later travels in the 1920s-1950s, essays and talks, poetry and translations of Spanish poetry by Meière, two novel length unpublished prose manuscripts, and travelogues. Early diaries include many enclosures, including photographs, drawings, calling cards, letters, and other keepsakes. A file of typescript memos and reports document Meière’s involvement with the National Society of Mural Painters’ Coordinating Committee during a turbulent period preceding the 1939 World’s Fair. Essays and talks concern Meière’s work on the 1939 New York World’s Fair, with the NYC WPA Art Project, and reflections on women in art careers, mural painting, and ecclesiastical art. Meière’s own poetry, as well as her translations of Spanish poets Gustavo Adolfo Becquer and others, are found in manuscript and typescript form. Enclosures found in an early handwritten volume of poetry called “Poems (so-called)” include a letter recounting the dissolution of her marriage in 1930. Two prose manuscripts include Battery Brown, written after the first World War, and a work Meière called her “Spanish Civil War Novella,” which is largely non-fiction documenting her experience with the Spanish war relief effort and her political stance on the conflict.
  Travelogues, handwritten and typewritten, are found for her trips to Constantinople and the Balkans, her trip to Russia in 1936, and her “Grand Tour” of 1952-1953, which began in Europe and moved through India, Indonesia, Australia, Sub-Saharan Africa, and ended in Great Britain during Queen Elizabeth II’s coronation. The Grand Tour is documented in a lengthy typescript travelogue. Also found is a short essay on the politics of the Arab Israeli conflict written after her trip to the Middle East in 1954.
  - Coordinating Committee Report, National Society of Mural Painters, 1938 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Diaries (Box 4)
    - Diaries, 1904; 1903; 1906; 3 volumes (Box 4, Folder 40)
    - Diary, 1906-1907 (Box 4, Folder 41)
    - Diary, 1907-1911 (Box 4, Folder 42)
    - Items Removed from Diary, 1907-1911 (Box 4, Folder 43)
    - Diary, 1912-1915 (Box 4, Folder 45)
    - Items Removed from Diary, 1912-1915 (Box 4, Folder 46)
    - Europe, 1922 (Box 4, Folder 47)
    - Europe and Russia, 1936 (Box 4, Folder 48)
    - Spain, 1938 (Box 4, Folder 49)
    - Yucatan, Mexico, 1946 (Box 4, Folder 50)
    - South America, 1947 (Box 4, Folder 51-53)
    - Grand Tour, 1952-1953 (Box 4, Folder 54-55)
    - Items Removed from Diary, Grand Tour, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 56)
    - Europe and Middle East, 1954-1955 (Box 4, Folder 57)
  - Essays and Talks (Box 4)
    - 11th Annual Friendship Dinner Press Release, 1937 November 16 (Box 4, Folder 58)
    - Associated Alumnae of the Sacred Heart, circa 1957 (Box 4, Folder 59)
    - At the Launching of the U.S.S. Buchanan, 1941 (Box 4, Folder 60)
    - "The Emancipation of Women", circa 1937 (Box 4, Folder 61)
    - "The Lord is God", 1911 (Box 4, Folder 62)
    - New York City WPA Art Project, circa 1941 (Box 4, Folder 63)
    - On the New York World's Fair from the Artist's Angle, circa 1939 (Box 4, Folder 64)
    - On the New York World's Fair, circa 1939 (Box 4, Folder 65)
    - On the Temple of Religion, to the Carroll Club, circa 1940 (Box 4, Folder 66)
    - Opportunities for Young Women in the Field of Art, 1934 (Box 4, Folder 67)
    - Pen and Brush Club, circa 1930-1960 (Box 4, Folder 68)
    - Proceedings of the Conference of Women's Work and their Stake in Public Affairs, 1935 (Box 4, Folder 69)
    - Rose Bay Association, Australia, 1952 (Box 4, Folder 70)
    - Working for a World's Fair, circa 1939 (Box 4, Folder 71)
  - Letter Book, "The Letters to Elizabeth", circa 1910 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Poetry (Box 5)
    - Poetry, circa 1905 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - "My Poems", 1907 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - "Poems (So-called)", 1904-1911 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Items Removed from "Poetry (So-called)", circa 1928-1930 (Box 5, Folder 5)
      Contains handwritten and typescript poems and letters, including a 1930 letter detailing the dissolution of her marriage.
    - Poetry, circa 1913-1940 (Box 5, Folder 6-7)
    - Poetry Translations, Gustavo Adolfo Bécquer, circa 1925 (Box 5, Folder 8-11)
      2 copies
    - Translations of Various Spanish Poets, circa 1925 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Prose (Box 5)
    - "Battery Brown", circa 1920 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Spanish Civil War Novella, circa 1938 (Box 5, Folder 14-18)
    - School Paper on Architecture, circa 1911 (Box 5, Folder 19-20)
  - Travelogues (Box 5)
    - Constantinople and the Balkans, 1933; Includes handwritten manuscript and typescript (Box 5, Folder 21-24)
    - Russia, 1936 (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Grand Tour, circa 1953 (Box 5, Folder 26-28)
    - Middle East, 1954 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Louise Meière UNICEF Work Notes, 1954 (Box 5, Folder 30)
- Civilian War Service Records, bulk 1938-1946; 1938-2006; Series 4; 0.7 Linear feet Boxes 5-6, 15, 28
  Records of Meière’s civilian war service document her efforts to aid Spain in the aftermath of the Spanish Civil War and to organize artists to contribute to the World War II effort. Extensive correspondence exists for both periods, as well as notes, memoranda, flyers, and reports. Material related to the Spanish Civil War also includes a transcript of a radio appearance by Meière, photographs of war devastation provided to her by Juan F. de Cárdenas, who would become Spain’s ambassador to the United States the following year, and three film reels (16mm) shot by Meière during a trip to Spain in 1938 as a guest of Franco’s government that document damage to public art and architecture as well as refugees. Also found are records related to an organization that came to be known as the America Spanish Relief Fund, which Meière helped to found.
  Records pertaining to World War II relief efforts include reports, correspondence, and other documentation of Meière’s organizing and volunteer coordination of various artist organizations for the creation of public art at military facilities across the United States. Also found are records relating to an event, “Vive La France,” organized to raise money for the benefit of French civilians affected by the war.
  See also Series 1, Biographical Materials for records regarding Meière’s service in the United States Navy in World War I and Business Correspondence in Series 2 for records related to the organization of the 1939 “Mass Meeting for America” featuring Martin Dies in which Meière participated, and for additional correspondence related to committees represented in this series. Photographic documentation of Meière’s extensive murals and designs made for military sites around the United States is found in series 7, Photographs and Moving Images.
  Existence and Location of Copies note
  Motion picture films in this series have been digitized for research access.
  - Spanish Civil War (Box 5)
    - Correspondence, 1938 (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - Correspondence, 1939 (Box 5, Folder 32)
      Includes letters from Anton Refregier and Juan F. de Cárdenas.
    - Correspondence, 1940-1946 (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - Committee to Send Anesthetics and Medicines to Spain, 1940-1943 (Box 5, Folder 34-35)
    - Gran Festival Campestre, Frente Popular Antifascista Gallego, 1938 (Box 5, Folder 36)
    - Memorandums, Reports, and Notes, 1938-1939 (Box 5, Folder 37)
    - Motion Picture Films by Hildreth Meière, 2006; 1938; 1 Videodiscs (DVD); 3 Film reels Original; all reels labeled "Spain refugee film," and one reel also labeled "San Sebastian to Toledo" 16 mm (Box 5, Folder 38)
      Film reels housed in Box 28
    - Photographs from Juan F. de Cárdenas, 1938 (Box 5, Folder 39-41)
    - Press Releases, Flyers, Circulars, and Clippings, 1939; 1942 (Box 5, Folder 42)
      Oversized newsletter in Box 15
    - Spanish Memo, "Services Provided by the Women's Section of the Spanish Falange of the JONS", circa 1938 (Box 5, Folder 43)
      In Spanish
    - Transcript of Radio Appearance by Hildreth Meière, 1939 (Box 5, Folder 44)
    - Travel Documents and Calling Cards, 1938 (Box 5, Folder 46)
  - World War II (Box 6)
    - "Vive La France" Benefit for French Civilian Relief, 1940 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - American Federation of the Arts and College Art Association, 1941 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Citizens Committee for Government Art Projects, 1941 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Citizens Committee for the Army and Navy, 1941-1946 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Joint Committee of the National Society of Mural Painters and the Architectural League, 1941 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Navy Young Men's Christian Association (Norfolk, VA), 1941 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - WPA Art Project for New York City, 1941 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Oversized Newsletter from Box 5, Folder 42 (Box 15)
  - Film Reel from Box 5, Folder 38 (Box 28)
- Travel Records, 1933-1958; Series 5; 9.8 Linear feet Boxes 6-10, 15, 28-33, OV 18
  Travel records are arranged in three subseries. Additional records related to Meiere’s travel are found throughout the collection.
  5.1: Travel Notes and Printed Material, 1936-1955
  5.2: Slides, 1946-1958
  5.3: Motion Picture Film, 1933-1958
  Travel Records include notes, printed material, slides, and motion picture film related to Meiere's many trips abroad between 1936 and 1958, throughout Europe, South and Central America, Indonesia, Australia, New Zealand, Sub-Saharan Africa, India, and Southeast Asia.
  - Travel Notes and Printed Material, 1936-1955; 5.1
    Travel notes and printed material include notes about travel destinations, which may have been made to carry out talks illustrated by the slides and films in this series. Printed materials include brochures, clippings, itineraries, and maps from Africa, Australia, New Zealand, Finland, India, Indonesia, the Soviet Union, and Thailand.
    Records are arranged alphabetically by region.
    - Notes, circa 1950-1955 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Africa (Box 6)
      - Brochures, circa 1953 (Box 6, Folder 10-11)
      - Clippings, 1954 (Box 6, Folder 12)
        Oversized Clippings in Box 15
      - Itinerary and Notes, 1953 (Box 6, Folder 13)
      - Maps, circa 1953 (Box 6, Folder 14-15)
        Oversized maps in OV 18
    - Australia and New Zealand (Box 6)
      - Brochures, circa 1952 (Box 6, Folder 16)
      - Clipping, circa 1952 (Box 6, Folder 17)
      - Itineraries and Maps, circa 1952 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Finland, Brochure, 1936 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - India (Box 6)
      - Brochures, circa 1952 (Box 6, Folder 20-21)
      - Clippings, 1953--1954 (Box 6, Folder 22)
        Oversized clippings in Box 15
      - Itinerary, 1952 (Box 6, Folder 23)
      - Maps, circa 1952 (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - Indonesia, Maps and Clipping, circa 1952 (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - Soviet Union (Box 6)
      - Brochures, circa 1936 (Box 6, Folder 26-27)
      - Maps, circa 1936 (Box 6, Folder 28)
    - Thailand (Box 6)
      - Brochures and Maps, circa 1952 (Box 6, Folder 29)
        Oversized map in OV 18
      - Clippings, 1954 (Box 6, Folder 30)
    - Oversized Clippings from Box 6, Folders 12 and 22 (Box 15)
    - Oversized Maps from Box 6, Folders 14, 24, and 29 (Box OV 18)
  - Slides, 1946-1958; 5.2 (Box 6)
    Slides in this series were taken during travels by Hildreth Meière and her daughter Louise Meière Dunn from the 1940s through the 1950s. Architecture, murals, and mosaics are highly represented in the images, and some landscape, local scenes, and personal photos are also found. Approximately one-half of the slides are from a lengthy trip Meière refers to in her writings as the “Grand Tour,” which began in Australia and New Zealand, and continued to Bali, Indonesia; Bangkok, Thailand; India; Sub-Saharan Africa; Italy; Great Britain; and France. While in England, they witnessed the coronation of Queen Elizabeth II. Other trips represented in travel slides include Mexico and Guatemala in 1946, South America in 1947, Italy in 1949-1950, Scandinavia in 1951, Middle Eastern countries referred to as the “Holy Land” trip in 1954, and Belgium in 1958, specifically to see the Belgian Fair of that year. Also found are a large set of slides of Italian Mosaics filed with slides from Italy. These and other identified sets appear to have been assembled for slide talks given by Louise and Hildreth Meière.
    There are no identifications on the slides themselves. Some sets of slides correspond to slide lists of subjects depicted but there are no comprehensive lists of subjects. Handwritten notes with general information about locations and artworks depicted are also found with some sets of slides, and may have been used in travel talks given by Hildreth and/or Louise Meière Dunn.
    Slides are arranged by country, some of which have several sets, the earliest encased in taped glass, and later sets in cardboard mounts. Where slide lists and/or notes about slide content exist they are filed directly before the set of slides they describe, and identified sets of slides are arranged in numerical order. Note that some sets of slides were given an original number sequence and then rearranged, presumably for lectures, so that lists are non-sequential. The order of identifications in these lists therefore does not always match the order of the slides, which are filed in numerical order when numbering exists. Where no lists of slides exist and slides have not been assigned numbers, slides are simply organized by country.
    - General Notes, circa 1950-1955 (Box 6, Folder 31)
    - Africa (Box 6)
      Locations depicted include Kenya, Tanzania, South Africa, Swaziland, South Africa, Rhodesia, Belgian Congo, and Uganda.
      - Slide List for Set 1, 1952-1953 (Box 6, Folder 32)
      - Set 1, 1952-1953; 3 slide boxes (Box 6, Folder 33-35)
      - Set 2, 1952-1953 (Box 6, Folder 36)
        Contains slide list
      - Set 3, 1952-1953 (Box 6, Folder 37)
    - Belgium, 1958 (Box 6, Folder 38)
    - England (Box 7)
      - England, circa 1953 (Box 7, Folder 1)
      - Oxford, circa 1953 (Box 7, Folder 2)
      - Queen Elizabeth II's Coronation, 1953 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Europe, Unidentified, circa 1950 (Box 7, Folder 4)
      Note in file indicates subjects include England, Belgium, Holland, Germany, Switzerland, France, and Austria.
    - France and Italy, Unidentified, circa 1950 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Guatemala, circa 1946 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Holy Land (Box 7)
      Locations depicted include Greece, Italy, Egypt, Turkey, Israel, Cyprus, Lebanon, and Syria
      - Notes for Set 1, circa 1954 (Box 7, Folder 7-8)
      - Set 1, 5 slide boxes (Box 7, Folder 9-13)
      - Set 2 (Box 7)
        - Greece, circa 1954 (Box 7, Folder 14-15)
        - Greece, Mosaics, circa 1954 (Box 7, Folder 16)
        - Istanbul, Turkey, circa 1954 (Box 7, Folder 17)
        - Istanbul, Turkey, Mosaics, circa 1954 (Box 7, Folder 18)
        - Cyprus, circa 1954 (Box 7, Folder 19)
        - Beirut Cedars, Lebanon, circa 1954 (Box 7, Folder 20)
        - Baalbek, Lebanon, circa 1954 (Box 7, Folder 21)
        - Damascus, Syria, circa 1954 (Box 7, Folder 22)
        - Egypt, circa 1954 (Box 7, Folder 23)
        - Israel, circa 1954 (Box 7, Folder 24)
        - Jerusalem, Israel, circa 1954 (Box 7, Folder 25)
        - Jerusalem and Bethlehem, Israel, circa 1954 (Box 7, Folder 26)
        - Unidentified, circa 1954 (Box 7, Folder 27)
    - India (Box 7)
      - Slide Lists and Notes, circa 1952 (Box 7, Folder 28)
      - Set 1, circa 1952; 3 slide boxes (Box 7, Folder 29-31)
    - India, Set 2, circa 1952 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Indonesia, Bali (Box 8)
      - Slide Lists and Notes, circa 1952 (Box 8, Folder 2)
      - Set 1, circa 1952; 2 slide boxes (Box 8, Folder 3-4)
      - Set 2, circa 1952 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Italy (Box 8)
      - Set 1, 1949-1950; 3 slide boxes (Box 8, Folder 6-8)
      - Set 2, Sicily, Taormina, 1953 (Box 8, Folder 9)
      - Set 3, 1957-1960 (Box 8, Folder 10-11)
    - Italian Mosaics (Box 8)
      - Slide List for Set 1, circa 1949-1950 (Box 8, Folder 12)
      - Set 1, circa 1949-1950; 2 slide boxes (Box 8, Folder 13-14)
      - Set 2, circa 1949-1960 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Mexico (Box 9)
      - Set 1, 1946; 3 slide boxes (Box 9, Folder 1-3)
        Subjects depicted include UNAM Mosaics, Monte Alban, Oaxaca, Puebla, Guadalajara, and the Diego Rivera and Rufino Tomayo murals.
      - Set 2, 1946 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - New Zealand and Australia (Box 9)
      - Slide Lists and Notes, circa 1952 (Box 9, Folder 5)
      - Set 1, New Zealand, circa 1952; 2 slide boxes (Box 9, Folder 6-7)
      - Set 2, New Zealand and Australia, circa 1952 (Box 9, Folder 8-9)
        Subjects depicted include Oxford and the Franz Josef Glacier, Ball Glacier, and Sydney and Melbourne, Australia.
    - Scandinavia (Box 9)
      - Set 1, circa 1951 (Box 9, Folder 10)
        Subject depicted is Sweden.
      - Set 2, circa 1951 (Box 9, Folder 11-17)